Patrick Coser

Oceanographer || Data Processor || Geoprocessing

Last update: May 14, 2024

Up-to-date version of CV is available at

https://patrickpca.github.io/cv-en

Local	♠ Espirito Santo
Linkedin	in Patrick-Coser
Github	○ <u>Patrickpca</u>
Email	patrickpcaa@gmail.com

Resume

As an Oceanographer with additional training in Cyber Defense from FIAP, I have specialized in the intersection between ocean science and data technology, with a focus on the acquisition, processing, and analysis of oceanographic data through advanced methods. My experience ranges from the use of bathymetric technologies and GIS analysis to the application of precise positioning systems, such as RTK and DGPS, in hydrographic and geophysical service projects. I possess solid skills in handling environmental data, such as ADCP, CTD profiles, dissolved oxygen, as well as data on waves, currents, sea levels, and meteorology. My proficiency in Python programming, enhanced by knowledge in data analysis and cybersecurity, allows for the development of efficient routines for processing and presenting oceanographic data. Experience in cybersecurity complements my analytical capability, bringing a rigorous approach to the protection, analysis, and management of sensitive data, essential for the integrity and security of oceanographic projects.

Professional Experience

October 2021 - Now

Freelance - DataProcessor

MBES processing through the softwares: QPS Qimera and FMGT, EIVA NaviEdit and Navimodel, Beamworx AutoClean and AutoPatch. Data validation, calibration, backscatter, quality control, deliverables production.

Multisource Data Integration: Combining bathymetric data with other geospatial data sources and phyton for comprehensive analysis.

Qimera	AutoClean	Eiva	NaviEdit	NaviModel	QGis	FMGT	Python	GlobalMapper	

November 2022 - Now

Mazars

- Internal and External Pentesting
- Pentesting on Web Applications
- Implementation of Security Policies following guidelines from CMN, Bacen, CVM, NIST, and ISO 27K
- Monitoring, auditing, and assessing the maturity of information security processes
- Analysis and mitigation of risks and vulnerabilities in cyber security systems, applications, processes, and infrastructures.
- Automate internal processes, creating interactive dashboards and web systems

Pentest	Audit	Vulnerability Assessment

April 2018 - July 2021

EGS Brasil

Data processing with Python and the development of technical reports for clients, incorporating automated methods for document creation using the language. Utilized libraries include Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Cartopy, Seaborn, gsw, pylab, and pycircstat. Maintenance, testing, and development of procedures for oceanographic electronic equipment such as SBES, ADCP, CTD and HOBO. Data acquisition via watercraft, conducting surveys, and installing tide gauges.

```
Data Analysis Python Geoprocessing
```

February 2016 - December 2016

Ecoceano - Junior Consulting Company in Oceanography and Environmental Education

Managing cash flow, preparing informative reports, conducting strategic planning, and supervising advisors in the distribution of tasks.



Education

- Cyber Defense Faculty of Informatics and Administration Paulista FIAP [2022]
- Bachelor's in Oceanography Federal University of Espírito Santo UFES [2018]

Experience

December 2016 - Now

Data Processor

Data analysis; Data qualification; Creation of data processing workflows; Automation of data processing.



January 2021 - Now

Cyber Security

 ${\tt Internal\ and\ External\ Pentesting;\ Web\ application\ pentest;\ Vulnerability\ analysis.}$



Projects

Date	Client	Project	Vessel	Software	Designation
Mar/2023 - Apr/2023	EGS	EGS UK - Sunderland	-	Qimera AutoClean FMGT QGis GlobalMapper Python	MBES Data Processor - Remote
Jul/2019 - Mar/2021	Petrobras	Shore Approach	Sem Limites	Github Python PHP Matlab ArcGis Qgis Autocad Hypack HOBOware Global Mapper Edgetech Discover SignatureWaves Echart Ruskin SeatermV2	Senior Geoscience Technician

Date	Client	Project	Vessel	Software	Designation
May/2021	Rede	Programa Amazônia	Maruaga	Python SeatermV2 Ruskin	Senior
-	Nacional de	Integrada Sustentável		ITER SYSTEMS BathySwath echosounder	Geoscience
Jun/2021	Ensino e	(PAIS)		SBG SYSTEMS Ellipse 2 MRU	Technician
	Pesquisa (RNP)			Teledyne DMS-05 MRU	
Oct/2021	EllaLink	Pre cable lay route	-	Python SeatermV2 Ruskin	Senior
		survey		ITER SYSTEMS BathySwath echosounder	Geoscience
				SBG SYSTEMS Ellipse 2 MRU	Technician
				Teledyne DMS-05 MRU	
Nov/2020	CELSE -	Centrais Eletricas de	-	Hypack Echart Scanline HOBOware	Senior
-	Centrais	Sergipe		Geosuite Acquisiton Edgetech Discover	Geoscience
Mar/2021	Elétricas de			Sonardyne Ranger Valeport Datalog Sonarwiz	Technician II
	Sergipe S.A			Qinsy Qimera	
Ago/2019	Alcatel	Malbec Submarine Cable	-	(Hypack) (Echart) (Scanline) (HOBOware)	Hydrography
-	Submarine	- Cable route survey in		Geosuite Acquisiton Edgetech Discover	Technical
Dez/2019	Network -	Rio de Janeiro and		Sonardyne Ranger Valeport Datalog Sonarwiz	Assistant III
	ASN	Santos - Brasil		Qinsy Qimera	
May/2019	TE SubCom	South Pacific Subsea	-	Hypack Python QGIS Qimera	Hydrography
- Jul/2019		Cable system		Global Mapper	Technical Assistant III
Oct/2018	Petrobras	Shore Approach	J.A.	Hypack Echart Scanline HOBOware	Freelance
-			Tibúrcio	Global Mapper Edgetech Discover	
Dec/2018				Nortek Aquadopp SIG500	